Jarreté Barnett

Full Stack Software Engineer

Contact

Address

South Windsor, CT, 06074

Phone

(860) 614-9019

E-mail

jy.barnett.io@gmail.com

Twitter

twitter.com/jarretedotio

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/jarretebarnett

WWW

jarretebarnett.github.io

Skills

CSS

Excellent

HTML

Excellent

SQL

Excellent

Git

Excellent

JavaScript

Very Good

JQuery

An experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with background in building and maintaining server database applications, as well as client-side rendering for intuitive and responsive operating systems. Proven analytical and problem-solving abilities, supported by intensive training and verifiable certifications in software engineering and server-side computer sciences. Versatile working habits suited for either team-oriented or remote work conditions. Established track record for pursuing new challenges, including those involving opportunities to learn new technologies, languages, coding libraries and frameworks.

Work History

2022-05 -Current

Associate Software Engineer

Turnberry Solutions, St. Louis, MO

- Team is tasked with the responsibility of developing and refining Pay with Points and Pay with Rewards features which offers users redemption rewards for eligible purchases
- Make daily collaborative effort with product managers to designate top priority stories that can be managed and completed within current or upcoming sprints and iterations
- Granted access to company repositories to modify applications and files as needed in order to optimize configuration and functionality, as well as eliminate any conflicting or obsolete code
- Discuss best practices with team members when necessary, and commit to bi-weekly elaborations on anemic design stories.

2020-02 -Current

Licensed Real Estate Sales Associate

William Raveis Real Estate Inc., Avon, CT

- Manage a personal CRM database of customers and clients
- Marketing for social media-centric engagement, reaching hundreds of active users monthly
- Prospecting inventory for seller interest, market data, and inquiring customers planning to buy or rent.

2021-11 -2022-04

Instructional Coach

The Coder School, Glastonbury, CT



- Provide support to students who are learning new software frameworks and languages.
- Relay notes of progress to both parents and internal administration.
- Refine students' skills in languages such as Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, etc.

2019-07 -2020-01

Licensed Real Estate Sales Associate

Keller Williams Realty, Glastonbury, CT

- Consultative experience with sellers inquiring about the marketability of their homes relative to existing inventory and proximity
- Managed client expectations proceeding closings, as well as the technical diligence required to research relevant property data for customers
- Closed over \$200,000 of volume within the first three months of licensure
- Effectively closed home purchases expediently in a six-week timeframe.

Education

2021-05 - 2021-07	Certification: Coding Bootcamp
	University of Connecticut - Storrs, CT
	No Degree: General Studies
	Manchester Community College - Manchester, CT
2000-09 - 2004-06	High School Diploma
	Howell Cheney Technical High School - Manchester, CT

Certifications

2021-07	UConn Coding Bootcamp
2021-08	Woz-U Application Development & Java Intensive
	Program